

Gülbahçe Mah. Eylül Apart No: 1, TURKEY

🛘 (+90) 554-791-6151 | 🗷 cilgaiscan@gmail.com | 🏕 www.cilgaiscan.me | 🖸 Cilgalscan | ե cilgaiscan | 🐧 cilgaiscan |

Summary_

Former part-time molecular biologist at a start-up company Urla Digital Agriculture. Specialized in bioinformatics, proteomics and plant genomics around 5 years hands-on-experience. Now, I am just a scientist-to-be who has an extreme curiosity to how internet works and how web-pages are built. Fascinated by colours of the nature and limit of imagination.

Education

Izmir Institute of Technology

İzmir, Turkey

B.S. IN MOLECULAR BIPLOGY AND GENETICS

Oct. 2013 - Present

Anadolu University

Eskişehir, Turkey

B.A. IN INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS

Oct. 2013 - Present

Skills

Programming R, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, JavaScript, Bash

Languages Turkish, English, German, Finnish

Biology RNA-seq, ChIP-seq, Mass Spectrometry, HPLC, PCR, cDNA Synthesis, Vector Design, Agroinfiltration

Experiences_

Urla Digital Agriculture

İzmir, Turkey

PART-TIME MOLECULAR BIOLOGIST

Jul. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Managed a project about yielding a human-specific enzyme, insulin, on tobacco and lettuce plants with using TMV-based agroinfiltration methodologies.
- Co-managing experiments about plant physiology and closed-controlled environment agriculture.

University of British Columbia & Vancouver Prostate Center

Vancouver, Canada

VISITING INTERNATIONAL RESEARCH STUDENT

Jun. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- Research student on functional genomics especially in prostate cancer patient' and primate prostate tissue.
- Manipulation of big human transcriptome assembly data and analysis using Bioconductor tools and Galaxy server.
- Built and implemented a RNA-seq and ChIP-seq workflow using R and Bash script.

Koç University İstanbul, Turkey

INTERN - VOLUNTEER

Jan. 2018 - Jun. 2018

- Analyzed expression levels of target gene KDM3B and its transcripts on different stages of cancer patients, re-current patients and healthy individuals provided by GDC and TCGA. (Total individuals 500)
- Created an R script to automatize calculation and visualisation process on large-scale patient input.

Abdullah Gül University

Kayseri, Turkey

INTERN - VOLUNTEER

Jan. 2017 - Feb. 2017

 Implementation of Python scripts to manipulate big data on Dream Challenge by DARPA, Sage Networks, IBM and more. Please check: https://www.synapse.org/#!Synapse:syn5647810/wiki/399103

Certificates

Agile with Atlassian Jira

Cousera Aug. 2020

Atlassian

Introduction to JavaScript

Cousera

University of Michigan

Aug. 2020

Introduction to CSS3 University of Michigan	Cousera Jun. 2020
Introduction to HTML5 University of Michigan	Cousera Jun. 2020
Introduction to HTML Coursera Guided Projects	Cousera Jun. 2020
Build Your Portfolio Website with HTML and CSS COURSERA GUIDED PROJECTS	Cousera Jun. 2020
Genomic Data Science with Galaxy John Hopkins University	Cousera Aug. 2019
Bioinformatic Methods II UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO	Cousera Feb. 2019
Bioinformatic Methods I UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO	Cousera Oct. 2018
Explonatory Data Analysis John Hopkins University	Cousera Oct. 2018
R Programming John Hopkins University	Cousera Jul. 2018

Honors & Awards _____

2008	5th Place , Tubitak Bu Benim Eserim Project Competition	Izmir, Turkey
2007	4th Place, Tubitak Bu Benim Eserim Project Competition	İzmir, Turkey
2018	Referee, Iztech Roboleague'18	İzmir, Turkey
2017	Referee, Iztech Roboleague'17	İzmir, Turkey
2015	Organization Commitee Member, Iztech Roboleague'15	İzmir, Turkey

Writing____

Kurmaca Arranged book

WRITER 2010

• Wrote a small poetry section in the book with my personal poems.

Renkli Gölgeler Arranged book

2014

WRITER

• Wrote a small poetry section in the book with my personal poems.